in previous videos we have addressed the
en vídeos anteriores hemos abordado el
case of Cindy the camps where we were able to
caso de Cindy the camps donde pudimos
see how various personalities in the
ver como diversas personalidades del
show business had been involved
espectáculo se habían visto involucradas
or affected by the parties that this
o afectada por las fiestas que este
character used to organize however what
personaje solía organizar sin embargo lo
until now only seemed like murmurs
que hasta ahora solo parecían murmullos
in the dark has taken a turn for the
en la oscuridad ha dado un giro por
first time someone has been
primera vez alguien ha quedado de manera
directly legally involved in this
directa involucrado legalmente en este
mess this time we are talking about jayc
enredo en esta ocasión hablamos de jayc
rapper producer businessman and
rapero productor empresario y actor
American actor whose career has been a
estadounidense cuya carrera ha sido un
pillar in the music industry now his
Pilar en la industria musical ahora su
name sounds like one of the first
nombre suena como uno de los primeros
formally involved in relation to
implicados formalmente en relación con
Didi the complaint points to him for
Didi la denuncia lo señala por
allegedly having been with a
presuntamente haber estado con una menor
minor and his appearance on this alleged
de edad y su aparición en esta presunta
list of celebrities involved has
lista de famosos involucrados ha
shaken the waters of public opinion
sacudido las aguas de la opinión pública
What's up my kids I'm Javi oliveira
Qué pasa mi chavalería Soy Javi oliveira
welcome one more day to my channel you already
bienvenidos un día más a mi canal ya
know that we are covering this case and
sabéis que estamos cubriendo este caso y
everything related to Didi from the
todo lo relacionado con Didi desde el
moment this arose So I did
primer momento que esto se levantó Así
n't want to be outdone and I wanted to give you
que no quería ser menos y quería daros
all the details of this famous
todos los detalles de esta famosa
accusation that is being made and is
acusación que está isando y se está
going viral on networks in the last
haciendo viral en redes en las últimas
hours You already know that on this channel you are going
horas Ya sabes que en este canal te vas
to find out about everything  internet gossip
a enterar de todo el chisme de internet
and all viral events So I
y de todos los sucesos virales Así que
recommend I do not force you to
te recomiendo No te obligo a que te
subscribe and like if you like this
suscribas y dale like si te gusta este
content let's get to the mess it is important
contenido vamos al lío es importante
Before talking about JC contextualize
Antes de hablar sobre JC contextualizar
the size of this character not only in
el tamaño de este personaje no solo en
the world of music but also in
el mundo de la música sino también en el
business he is a very
de los negocios es una persona muy
important person jayc was born in
importante jayc nació en el año
1969 very early in his life his father
1969 muy pronto en su vida su padre lo
abandoned him and at age 12 as he confessed he
abandonó y a los 12 años según confesó
took a gun since according to he
el mismo cogió un arma ya que según
indicated everywhere in his house
indicaba por todos lados de su casa
were accessible to
estaban accesibles para cualquier
anyone and shot his brother Eric in the shoulder
persona y disparó en el hombro a su
who was a
hermano Eric quien era un adicto a las
drug addict for having stolen some jewelry
drogas por haberle robado unas joyas sin
however JC apologized to him as he
embargo JC Se disculpó con él ya que
indicated that he understood the issue of
indicó que entendía el tema de la
addiction and that was what had
adicción y que eso era lo que había
led to making that mistake and for that
llevado a cometer ese error y por esa
reason his brother did not press charges
razón su hermano no levantó cargos en su
against him in his high school time was
contra en su tiempo de secundaria fue
where he had contact with the world of Rap
donde tuvo contacto con el mundo del Rap
since he met two quite
ya Que conoció a dos raperos bastante
important rappers before today such as
importantes antes en la actualidad como
notorious Big and bosta rim his mother
lo son notorius Big y bosta rim su madre
Gloria Carter  He bought him a radio
Gloria Carter le compró un radio
cassette player that sparked in J JC
cassette aparato que despertó en el J JC
an interest in music and
el interés en la música y la
improvisation a situation that led him to
improvisación situación que lo llevó a
participate in various competitions that
participar en varias competiciones que
in the future would allow him to join a
en el futuro le permitirían unirse a un
record label from here on out all
sello discográfico a partir de aquí todo
Success for the rapper in addition to fights
Éxito para el rapero además de peleas
with other rappers currently JC is one
con otros raperos actualmente JC es uno
of the most successful and financially influential hip-hop artists
de los artistas de hip-hop más exitosos
in the world
y económicamente influyentes en el mundo
with an estimated net worth of more
con un patrimonio neto estimado en más
than 2.5 billion in 2024 we are
de 2,500 millones en 2024 estamos
talking about more than double the net worth
hablando de más del doble del patrimonio
that Michael Jackson was supposed to have
que se suponía que tenía Michael Jackson
since Michael Jackson was estimated to
ya que a Michael Jackson se estimaba que
have Well I think he even
tenía Bueno creo que él incluso llegó a
acknowledged it more or less in a mid-
reconocerlo más o menos en una medio
interview 1 billion dollars
entrevista 1000 millones de dólares a lo
throughout his career he has sold around
largo de su carrera ha vendido alrededor
75 million albums globally
de 75 millones de álbumes a nivel global
and has been nominated no more and no less than
y ha sido nominado Ni más ni menos que
83 times for the Grammy Awards
83 veces a los premios gramy
becoming the musician with the most
convirtiéndose en el músico con más
nominations in the history of these
nominaciones en la historia de estos
awards of which he has won 23
premios de los cuales ha ganado 23
awards considered one of the
galardones considerado como uno de los
best rappers of all time on
mejores raperos de todos los tiempos en
TV positioned him at number one in its
tv lo posicionó en el número uno de sus
lists for rappers in
listas en cantantes de rap en el año
2006 best albums all
2006 best albums all
Time Of One of the best albums all
Time Of One of the best albums all
absolutely album all time you know what I'm saying
absolutely album all time you know what
Just the time we was living
I'm saying Just the time we was living
what I was going through And I mean that was
what I was going through And I mean that
my whole album my whole life making that
was my whole album my whole life making
album you know what I'm saying
that album you know what I'm saying
That's why so de To Me and it Was and It
That's why so de To Me and it Was and It
was all real It was real emotion It was
was all real It was real emotion It was
you got to Look at it it looked at it it looked at
you got to Look at it it looked at it it
Life from so many different
looked at Life from so many different
aspects from betrayal on the evils you
aspects from betrayal on the evils you
know what I'm saying to to Being vulnerable
know what I'm saying
on regrets you
to to Being vulnerable on regrets you
know what I'm saying to to dealing with
know what I'm saying to to dealing with
you know politics as Us to Just having
you know politics as Us to Just having
Club albums are considered milestones
Club álbumes son considerados como hitos
in hip hop and are listed on Rolling Stone's list of
en El hip hop y figuran en la lista de
the 500 greatest albums of all
los 500 mejores álbumes de todos los
time and this same
tiempos de Rolling Stone y esta misma
magazine also recognized him as one of
revista también lo reconoció como uno de
the 100 greatest artists in history
los 100 mejores artistas de la historia
placing him at number 88 but JC has not
ubicándolo en el puesto 88 pero JC no
only left his mark in music
solo ha dejado su huella en la música
but also in the world of
sino que también en el mundo de los
business and investments he is
negocios y las inversiones es
co-owner of  141 Club an exclusive
copropietario del 141 Club un exclusivo
sports bar is also one of the
bar deportivo es también uno de los
owners of the
dueños de la franquicia de baloncesto
Brooklyn Net NBA basketball franchise and creator of
Brooklyn net de la NBA y creador de de
the successful Roca Weir clothing line which has
la exitosa línea de ropa roca weir que
become a pillar in
se ha convertido en un Pilar en la moda
urban fashion in the executive field he was the seo
urbana en el ámbito ejecutivo fue el seo
of Death Jum Recordings one of the
de Death jum recordings una de las
most influential record labels in hip
discográficas más influyentes del hip
hop at the moment in addition to being
hop en estos momentos además de ser
co-founder of Rock Afela Records and
cofundador de rock afela Records y
founder of Rock Na a powerful
fundador de rock na una poderosa
entertainment company that manages
compañía de entretenimiento que gestiona
artists athletes and
artistas deportistas y producciones
global productions in 2008 he also married
globales en el año 2008 se casó también
the successful singer Villon Cé with
con la exitosa cantante villon cé con
whom he has had three children it is
quien ha tenido tres hijos es de
public knowledge that they have had a
conocimiento público que han tenido una
somewhat turbulent relationship that has gone
relación algo turbulenta que ha pasado
through several alleged infidelities on the
por varias supuestas infidelidades por
part of the rapper and then
parte del rapero y luego
reconciliations surviv when you
reconciliaciones surviv when you
Survival What happen Shut down you Shut down all
Survival What happen Shut down you Shut
emotions right so even with
down all emotions right so even with
women you got Shut down emotionally So
women you got Shut down emotionally So
You
You
Connect all things happen from there
Connect all things happen from there
[Music]
[Música]
in the late 90s JC would meet
a finales de los años 90 JC conocería a
who by then was already more
quien para ese entonces ya estaba más
than consolidated in the world of music I'm
que consolidado en el mundo de la música
talking about SIM didy  cams that happened
os hablo de SIM didy cams eso pasó
when JC was beginning to gain
cuando JC comenzaba a ganar
recognition in the rap industry
reconocimiento en la industria del rap
at first their paths
en un primer momento sus caminos se
crossed through the
cruzaron a través de la escena del hip
New York hip hop scene Didi who at that
hop de Nueva York Didi quien en ese
time was already an influential figure
entonces ya era una figura influyente
with his serious Bad Boy record had
con su serio Bad Boy record había
heard about JC and his emerging talent
escuchado sobre JC y su talento
[Music]
[Música]
Although it is true that it came to be seen as
Aunque es verdad que llegó a ver como
a rivalry between the two especially
una rivalidad entre ambos sobre todo
due to the competition in the
debido a la competencia en el ámbito
musical field and the perception of enemies that
musical y la percepción de enemigos que
existed in the music industry at
se tenía en la industria de la música
that time, in turn
por aquel entonces a su vez Se generó
a mutual relationship of respect was generated between them over
una relación mutua de respeto entre con
time Didi began to recognize
el tiempo Didi empezó a reconocer el
JC's potential and his ability to
potencial de JC y su habilidad para
build a successful career which
construir una carrera exitosa lo que les
allowed them to collaborate on several occasions and
permitió colaborar en varias ocasiones y
finally forge a
finalmente forjar una relación
close professional relationship and it is here where
profesional cercana y es aquí donde se
one of the worst decisions in
dio una de las peores decisiones en la
JC's life occurred, getting involved with Cindy Camp And
vida de JC involucrarse con Cindy Camp Y
since Camp was accused by
es que desde que Camp fue acusado por
federal prosecutors in a
Fiscales federales en una investigación
sex trafficking investigation,
de tráfico sexual se han presentado
numerous civil lawsuits have been filed by people
numerosas demandas civiles de personas
who claim to have been victims of the
que afirman haber sido víctimas del
artist, there have also been suggestions of
artista también ha habido sugerencias de
other big names that were going to be
otros grandes nombres que se iban a ver
dragged in. And such was the case with JC
arrastrados Y así fue el caso de JC
who  On Sunday, December 8 of this
quien el domingo 8 de diciembre de este
same year in which I am uploading this
mismo año en el que estoy subiendo Este
video, I received news of an
vídeo Recibió la noticia de una demanda
anonymous civil lawsuit that I do not understand much
civil anónima que yo no entiendo mucho
why in the United States
por qué en Estados Unidos se pueden
anonymous lawsuits can be filed, we have already
presentar demandas anónimas ya hemos
seen that she also has a Didi,
visto que también tiene una Didi de la
which well, they are asking that it not be
que bueno pues están pidiendo que no sea
anonymous in order to defend themselves, it is
anónima para poderse defender es que
sincerely not to defend
sinceramente no es por defender a
either of these two but that someone
ninguno de estos dos pero que alguien te
can file a lawsuit against you It causes you a
pueda poner una demanda Te causa una
situation of defenselessness that
situación de indefensión que no se
should not be allowed apparently the lawsuit
debería permitir al parecer la demanda
comes from a girl who calls herself
viene por una chica que se hace llamar
Jane do and I say that she calls herself
como Jane do y digo que se hace llamar
because I already told you that the lawsuit is
porque ya os digo que la demanda es
anonymous and this name is used in the
anónima y este nombre se utiliza en
United States to refer to
Estados Unidos para hacer referencia a
an anonymous person in her complaint the
una persona anónima en su denuncia la
girl reports that in the year 2000 when she
chica informa que en el año 2000 cuando
was only 13 years old both JC and
tenía solamente 13 años tanto JC como
Didi of her the incident supposedly
Didi de ella el hecho supuestamente
occurred at a party after the
ocurrió en una fiesta posterior a los
NTV Music Video Awards the
ntv music video Awards la demanda
original lawsuit against Cindy de Camp was
original contra Cindy de Camp fue
filed in October 2024 in the
presentada en octubre del 2024 en el
Southern District of New York initially
distrito sur de Nueva York inicialmente
only mentioning him as the defendant
solo mencionándolo a él como demandado
however on December 8, attorney
sin embargo el 8 de diciembre el abogado
Tony Bosby returned  to file the case and
Tony bosby volvió a presentar el caso y
added JC as one of the defendants JC
agregó a JC como uno de los acusados JC
for his part in a statement to Us
por su parte en un comunicado en el Us
Weekly addressed
weekly se dirigió directamente al
attorney Tommy Busby directly saying the
abogado Tommy bosby diciendo lo
following my attorney received an attempted
siguiente mi abogado recibió un intento
blackmail call a demand letter
de chantaje llamado una carta de demanda
from an attorney named Tony Busby what
de un abogado llamado Tony busby lo que
he had calculated was that the nature
él había calculado era que la naturaleza
of these allegations and the
de estas acusaciones y el escrutinio
public scrutiny would make me want to settle
público me harían querer llegar a un
No sir it had the
acuerdo No señor tuvo el efecto con
opposite effect it made me want to expose you for
contrario me hizo querer exponerte por
the fraud that you commit in a very
el fraude que cometes de una manera muy
public way so no I will not give you a
pública Así que no no te daré ni un
penny these accusations are of
centavo estas acusaciones son de una
such a heinous nature that I implore you to
naturaleza tan atroz que te imploro que
file a criminal complaint not a
presentes una denuncia criminal no una
civil one anyone who commits such a crime
civil cualquiera que Cometa tal crimen
against a minor should be incarcerated would
contra un menor Debería ser encarcelado
you not agree these alleged
no estarías de acuerdo estas supuestas
victims would deserve true
víctimas merecerían una verdadera
justice if that were the case in this
justicia si ese fuera el caso en este
statement J focuses on pointing out that
comunicado J se centra en señalar que
given the seriousness of the accusation they
dada la gravedad de la acusación que
are making it is logical that a
están haciendo lo lógico es que una
person would want justice and that they
persona persona quisiera justicia y que
would have filed a criminal complaint not
hubiesen puesto una denuncia penal no
a civil suit to seek PTA this
una demanda civil para pedir pta este
attorney on whom I have investigated a
abogado sobre el cual er investigado un
bit seems to have a pattern of this type
poco parece tener un patrón de este tipo
of theatrics I have no idea  how
de teatralidades No tengo idea de cómo
you came to be such a
has llegado a ser un ser humano tan
deplorable human being Mr. Bosby but I promise you I've
deplorable señor bosby pero te prometo
seen plenty of your kind I'm
que he visto a muchos de tu tipo estoy
more than prepared to deal with your
más que preparado para lidiar con tu
kind you've made a terrible error in
clase has cometido un terrible error de
judgment thinking all
juicio al pensar que todas las
celebrities are the same I'm not of
celebridades son iguales no pertenezco a
your world I'm a young man who came out of the
tu mundo soy un joven que salió del
Brooklyn project we don't play these
proyecto de Brooklyn no jugamos este
kinds of games we have very strict codes and honor
tipo de juegos tenemos códigos y honor
we protect children you
muy estrictos protegemos a los niños tú
seem to exploit people for
pareces explotar a las personas para
personal gain only your network of
beneficio personal solo tu red de
fake physics conspiracy theorists will
teóricos de la conspiración física falsa
believe the idiotic claims you've
creerá las afirmaciones idiotas que has
brought against me that if it weren't for
presentado contra mí que si no fuera por
the seriousness related to the harm to
la seriedad relacionada con el daño a
children they would be laughable I very much look forward to
los niños serían risibles espero con
showing you how different I am that you
ansias mostrarte lo diferente que soy
find it curious to say the least that
que le resulta curioso cuanto menos que
a supposedly victim of these
una víctima supuestamente de estos
events who has trauma and reports it
hechos que tiene un trauma y lo denuncia
almost 30 years later asks for money, in other
casi 30 años después pues pida dinero o
words instead of asking for justice not criminal not to be
sea en vez de pedir justicia no penal no
put in jail what he's
que lo metan en la cárcel Lo que está
asking for is money in this way JC
pidiendo es pasta de esta manera JC
made it clear that he has nothing to
dejaba Claro que él no tiene nada que
do with these accusations that are being
ver con esas acusaciones que le están
attributed to him and that he was
achacando y que estaba siendo
allegedly being extorted well
presuntamente extorsionado bueno
basically yes what  what he's
básicamente sí lo que está dando a
implying is that this is something similar to
entender es que esto es algo parecido a
what happened to Michael Jackson in one
lo que le pasó a Michael Jackson en una
of the accusations, basically the
de las acusaciones básicamente la
person who was reporting. Well, he
persona que estaba denunciando Pues
wanted money and this also happens in
quería dinero y esto pasa también en
many cases of celebrities, not that they ask for
muchos casos de famosos no que piden
money in exchange not for reporting but
pasta a cambio ya no de denunciar sino
for not coming out in the media
de no salir tampoco mediáticamente ente
to say that you're going to report. There are many
a decir que vas a denunciar hay muchos
celebrities who agree to these issues, to
famosos que acceden a estas cuestiones a
this type of extortion. I don't know if
este tipo de extorsión que no sé si
this is still the case or not, but there are
todavía esto lo será o no pero hay
many who tend to accept despite being
muchos que suelen aceptar a pesar de ser
innocent to avoid problems
inocente por quitarse problemas de
and it's faster for them to
encima y le es más rápido a lo mejor
pay an amount that doesn't cost them
pagar una cantidad que no le suponga
much than to get involved in a
mucho a verse involucrado en una
controversy that you want or not, and then however it turns out, Well,
polémica que quieras que no ya luego
your image is always going to be stained and not
quedar manchada en tu imagen y no el
100% of the people are going to find out after
100% de la gente se va a enterar después
the truth is revealed, they are going to be left with the
de la verdad se va a quedar con la
accusation. List already, and of course, I
acusación list already and of course I
already know who some of these individuals are, but
already know Who some of these
because of the nature
individuals are but Because the nature
of this case, we're going to make damn sure, damn sure that we're right before we do that, but
of this Case we're going to make damn
the names that we're
we do that but the names that we're
going to name, assuming that, our
Going To name assuming that Our
investigators  confirm and corroborate
investigators confirm and corroborate
what we've been told or names that will shock you
What we've been told or names that Will
these are individual cases
shock you these are individual cases
there are indeed other perpetrators
there are indeed other perpetrators
involved they will be revealed when that
involved they will be revealed When that
particular individual case is ready to be filed
particular individual Case is ready to
they already know who they are
be filed they already know Who They are
and I'm talking here about
and I'm talking here about
despite this whole situation that is
a pesar de toda esta situación que está
happening JC has continued with his life as
pasando JC ha seguido con su vida como
if nothing was happening even showing up
si nada estuviera pasando presentándose
on the red carpet of the Lion King
incluso a la alfombra roja del Rey León
The other day having supposed doubts on
El otro día habiendo supuestas dudas por
Disney's part for him to
parte de Disney para que este
participate but with Bon interfering
participase pero con Bon interfiriendo
so that they would allow him to be with him in
para que le permitieran estar con él de
fact there are many people on social networks who are
hecho hay mucha gente en redes que está
criticizing billionaire for appearing on
criticando a billon se por aparecer en
this carpet and acting as if nothing
esta alfombra y actuar como si nada
was happening something that they have already done
estuviera pasando cosa que ya han hecho
with other previous cases no and it
también con otros casos anteriores no y
is that in the end let's see if he is
es que al final e a ver si está
involved much worse no but in the
involucrado muchísimo peor no pero al
end they do not stop having a relationship
final ellos e no dejan de tener relación
with Didi currently no and of being very
con Didi actualmente no y de estar muy
related to him no and in the past we
relacionados con él no y ya atrás
were commenting on another video that she
estuvimos comentando en otro vídeo que
was receiving a lot of hate in the
le estaba cayendo mucho hate en la caja
comments box of her networks no and that
de comentarios de sus redes no y que
she was trying to ignore it for being
ella estaba intentando ignorar por estar
related to this man and not
relacionada con este hombre y no
speaking out respect when the majority
pronunciarse respeto cuando la mayoría
of celebrities have made some mention
de famosos pues alguna mención han hecho
against not disassociating himself no and
en contra no desvinculándose no y
obviously condemning the situation and
condenando evidentemente la situación y
everything that
todo lo que parece ser que ha hecho
that man Didi seems to have done as we have seen
aquel hombre el Didi como ya hemos visto
throughout all the videos that we have
a lo largo de todos los vídeos que hemos
made on this subject one of the
hecho sobre este tema una de las
celebrities who has spoken out the most
celebridades que más se ha pronunciado
against Didi condemning his actions
en contra de Didi condenando sus actos
has been F sen And the thing is that really The
ha sido F sen Y es que realmente El
rapper well apart from condemning these
rapero pues aparte de que condene estos
acts obviously despite the fact that well he
actos evidentemente a pesar de que bueno
also has his things no
también tiene sus movidas no
obviously not comparable to those of
evidentemente no comparables con las de
Didi he does maintain a bad relationship
Didi sí que mantiene una mala relación
with him the other day we spoke with f and n he
con el el otro día hablamos con f y n
said that you invited him to buy some
dijo que tú lo invitaste a comprarse
clothes he told me that he was taking me
ropa él me dijo que me llevaba de
shopping So I said Hey what the [ __ ] did you
compras Entonces le digo Oye qué carajos
tell me yeah I thought I needed clothes
me dijiste sí pensé que necesitaba ropa
The problem is that he said it to me very
El problema es que me lo dijo muy
affectionately I'm a cute guy what's up Oh
cariñoso soy un tipo lindo qué pasa Oh
That's a cute G and I was like no
Eso es un lindo G y yo me estaba por no
like menico it was like if I were saying it to
como menico fue como si se lo dijera a
a girl you know that he loves me not in that
una chica sabes que él me ama no de esa
way besides how he looked at me it made me
forma además de cóm me miraba me hizo
feel
sentir
uncomfortable he mentioned that the national
incómodo mencionó que la liga nacional
soccer league could probably end its
de fút probablemente podría terminar su
association with JC and Rock na as a
asociación con JC y Rock na como
result  of these accusations and that
resultado de estas acusaciones y que se
are going viral so much, I don't know if this is
están viralizando tanto no si esto Se
confirmed because it represents a
confirma pues representa una pérdida
pretty million dollar loss, I don't know if it will
bastante millonaria no sé si le hará
hurt him much or not, but well, quite a
mucho daño o no pero bueno bastante
million dollar loss for JC and like
pérdida millonaria para JC y al igual
this one, I think other
que esta yo creo que se le caerán otras
collaborations will fall through because the truth is that
colaboraciones porque la verdad es que
right now the subject is very hot.
ahora mismo el tema está muy calentito
But well, we'll see what
Pero bueno ya veremos a ver qué es lo
happens, at the moment this is where we
que pasa de momento hasta aquí es donde
know. I hope it was clear to you,
se sabe Espero que os haya quedado Claro
if you have something to ask me, you can
si tenéis algo que preguntarme podéis
do it in the comments box, you
hacerlo en la caja de comentarios ya
know that we are covering the whole
sabéis que estamos cubriendo todo el
subject, so subscribe, activate the
tema así suscribiros activar la
bell, share and all that stuff.
campanita compartir y todas esas cosas
If you are interested in this subject, a kiss, family,
Si te interesa este tema un beso familia
see you in the next one and bye bye
nos vemos en el próximo y chao chao
[Music]
[Música]